本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译   米小勒    kiko    CS小明漫画家     我叫魏碧慧
翻译   迷失重生教堂   Marshal同学   天启章鱼X   lottie筱妤
时间轴   太太乐叽叽    SumenQ       后期   小亲斤
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第七集
《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on "Z Nation".
一颗穿心的子弹即可揭示真相
A bullet to the heart will reveal the truth.
不要
No!
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
沃伦  我们得走了
Warren, we have to go.
-不  -我们得马上走
- No. - We have to go now!
我们不能让他变异
We can't let him turn.
我们必须对他"施以仁慈"
We have to give him mercy!
大家早上好
Good morning, people.
欢迎来到僵尸爆发第三年
Welcome to the third day of the sixth month
零六个月的第三天
of the year 03 A.Z.
如果你现在在听着广播  说明你还活着
If you're listening to this, it means you're still alive.
那么必须得恭喜一下了
So congratulations.
亦或者同情一下了
Or condolences.
欢迎来到堪萨斯
你们懂得  这已无关紧要
You know, whatever.
如果你注意到了我今天的声音比以往都要来的绝望
If you're noticing more despair in my voice than usual today,
那是因为我们失去了一个特殊的人
it's because we lost someone special.
我知道  我们一直都在失去着身边的人
I know, we lose people all the time.
被丧尸咬掉脸颊比活着撑到
Getting your face chewed off by a Z is more common
你下一个生日要容易得多
than making it to your next birthday.
但这个家伙...
But this guy...
这是一位值得提及的人物
This one's worth mentioning.
查尔斯·加内特  陆军国民警卫队预备役中士
Charles Garnett, First Sergeant, Army National Guard Reservist,
是一位对上帝  对生活  虔诚的好人
was an honest to God, real life, actual good guy.
他并不只为了自己  他还为别人而战
He fought for other people, not just for his own survival.
他在最近的日子里  完成了很多不可能完成的任务
And he did something that's pretty much impossible these days.
他给人们带来了希望
He gave people hope.
还记得希望为何物吗
Remember hope?
还记得我们也曾想象过  我们也许最终
Remember thinking that we might actually
真的会挺过这次灾难吗
come out on the other side of this thing?
是的  就是那希望
Yeah. That.
加内特中士为了带给我们这样一个希望而死
Sergeant Garnett died trying to give us a reason to hope.
出于您的行为...
And for that...
查尔斯·加内特中士
Sergeant Charles Garnett.
我仅代表这个伟大的国度
On behalf of a grateful nation,
不管我们现在变成了何等鬼样子
or whatever the hell we are now,
我们向您致敬
we salute you.
又是散热器吗
Radiator?
是啊
Yeah.
修得了吗
Fixable?
说不准
Don't know.
汗  我们要能有个机修工该多好
Gee, if we only had a mechanic.
老兄  你得让她自己缓缓
You got to let her deal, man.
她有创伤后的压力嘛
She's got that post-traumatic stress.
她有创伤后的压力  呵呵
She's got post-traumatic stress?
全世界都有创伤后的压力好吗
The whole world's got post-traumatic stress.
实际上根本没有关于这玩意的确切说法
Actually there isn't anything post about it.
我们现在所有人一直都会有那些
We all got plain ol' present tense,
什么创伤啦  压力之类的
all traumatic, all stress all the time.
怎么就非要对她特殊照顾
What makes her so special?
喂  醒醒了  喂
Hey. Wake up. Hey.
不  你不能就坐这看光景
No, you can't just check out.
我们有任务要完成
We got a job to do.
我现在也没多少时间了
And I am running out of time.
距离加利福尼亚还有2000里的恶路要走
And California is still 2,000 miles of bad road away.
没有你的带领  我们是到不了的
And we are not gonna make it without you.
因为他们接下来不会听我的
Cuz it's not like they're gonna follow me
也不会听老头子的或是摩托车上那俩奇葩的
or the old man or the wonder twins out there.
喂
Hey.
好吧  我和安迪去前面探探路
All right, Addy and I will scout up ahead.
看看能不能找到帮手
See if we can get some help.
我们去找吗
We will?
对
Yeah.
额  我也不确定  但我觉得我们该待在一起
Yeah, I don't know guys. I think we should stick together.
不  多克  不用担心
No, Doc. Don't worry.
我们就去前面兜一圈然后就回来找你们
We're just gonna scout ahead and circle back around and find you.
反正你们在卡车里也跑不远
I mean it's not like you're getting far in the truck.
快来吧  安迪
Come on, Addy.
我也不敢相信我会这么说  不过
I can't believe I'm saying this, but
如果沃伦一直走不出来怎么办
what if Warren doesn't snap out of it?
她不会就此放弃的
She's not giving up.
行吧  但我们
All right, well
也不可能坐以待毙奢望帮助会自动上门吧
we can't just sit here and wait for help to come.
我们得做点什么
I mean we got to do something.
好吧
Okay.
我找到散热器水管上的漏洞了
I found the leak in the radiator hose.
我补了一下  不过
Taped it up a little bit, but
要往里面倒点水  我们才能继续上路
we're not going anywhere unless we get some water in there.
我渴了
I get thirsty.
大家都很渴
We all get thirsty.
我来开车
I'll drive.
随便开  孩子
Knock yourself out, kid.
悠着点  孩子
Easy there, kid! Easy!
谁教你开的车
Who taught you how to drive?
没人教过我
No one.
手放在方向盘十点和两点的位置
Hands on the ten and the two.
轻踩油门
And easy on the gas.
这里什么都没有
Nothin' out here.
没人  没汽油  连僵尸都没有
No people, no gas, not even Zs.
算了  我们回去吧
Nah, we got to go back.
这里没什么能帮得上忙
There is no help out here.
回去也一样
There's no help back there either.
我们必须要回去  麦克
We have to go back, Mack.
我们有任务在身
We have a mission.
我们许下了承诺
We made a promise.
其实  我们并没有
No, we didn't.
我们从来都没承诺什么
We never did.
艾迪  我们只对彼此许下了承诺
Addy, the only promise we ever made was to each other.
努力活下去
To stay alive.
是的  没错
Look, yeah, okay.
也许我们没有说出来  也没有签署誓约
Maybe we didn't say the words and we didn't sign an oath.
但是大家互相照应
But we all stand for each other.
谁也不会丢下别人不管
We don't leave each other behind.
我被食人族绑架后  加内特还回来救我
Garnett came back for me when those cannibals kidnapped me.
你现在却想丢下沃伦扬长而去吗
And now you want to leave Warren?
她需要我们
She needs us.
大家都需要我们
They all need us.
我只是在想
I just think
也许我们单打独斗会有更好的机会
maybe we have a better chance on our own.
就像开始那样
Like in the beginning.
有多久了
So how long?
什么
What?
你多久之前就开始意识到
How long before you think that you have a better chance
你自己有更好的机会
on your own?
艾迪  慢着
Addy. Whoa.
我回来都是为了你
I came back for you.
那些食人族
The cannibals.
我是为你而回  我以后也会这样做
I came back for you. I'll always come back for you.
你了解我的
You know me.
我不太确定了
I'm not so sure anymore.
我现在对任何事都不确定了
About anything.
好吧
All right.
我们回去吧
We'll go back.
好的
Okay.
往右边开
Go right.
为什么
Why right?
为什么不
Why not?
没有僵尸
No Zs.
那是个好迹象
That's a good sign.
枪械展会  就在今日
越来越有意思了
Getting interesting.
酒  这才像话
Liquor! Now you're talking.
摩菲  我们应该经常让你带路
Murphy, we're gonna have to let you navigate more often.
恭喜你  孩子  你现在是代驾司机了
Congratulations, son. You're now the designated driver.
什么意思
What's that mean?
意思是  猛踩油门
It means step on it!
我从没见过这么多僵尸聚在一起
I've never seen so many in one place.
重返大部队计划到此为止
So much for going back.
停车
Stop.
你们都有武器吗
Y'all armed?
那还用说
Obviously.
很好  我们可没时间照顾别人
Good. We don't have time to babysit anyone.
枪和酒
Guns and liquor.
还能出什么问题
What could go wrong?
刚刚有人提到酒吗
Did anyone say liquor?
好好欣赏展会  小伙子们
Enjoy the show fellas.
欢迎来到S&S股份有限公司
Welcome to S&S Limited,
这里有西部最棒的枪械展览
the finest gun show in the west.
入场费是七
Entry fee is seven.
七个什么
Seven what?
子弹
Bullets.
氧气弹
Oxy.
或者你们还有别的什么能嗨翻天的玩意
Grams of whatever DIY super fun time substance you got.
我记得后车厢里还有点冰毒
Well I think I got some crystal back in the truck.
那玩意也很不错
It's the good stuff too.
那些垃圾货色你自己收着
Back off with the toilet bowl cleanser meth.
我们只收真正的冰毒
We only take that genuine
得是那种能让你忘记末日来临
vein splittin' take you right out of this beautiful apocalypse
感觉置身于世外仙境的刺激玩意
and into a hell-hole meth.
真他妈吓了我一跳
Well slap my ass and call me Sally
竟然是斯盖齐 ·麦克莱恩
if it ain't Sketchy McClain.
你怎么会到这里来了
How'd you get way out here?
我们一路做着买卖过来的
We traded our way up in the world.
这边走
Here.
要知道僵尸行动起来毫无章法可言
You see zombies, they move in mysterious ways.
我们当时快撑不下去了
We were on our last legs when we came upon this
碰巧遇到僵尸在攻击这辆满载武器的卡车
truckload of sweet weaponry under attack.
我们不得不对前任主人施以仁慈
We had to give the former owners mercy.
作为回报
And in return,
他们给了我们这辆好车
they gave us this wonderful vehicle with
我们就这么开到了堪萨斯州
enough gas to get us here to Kansas.
斯基齐
Hey, Skeezy!
看看僵尸们带来了谁
Look what the living dead dragged in!
多克
Doc!
我听说你死在蓝天营了
I heard you were toast back at Camp Blue Sky!
别傻站着  快过来
Don't just stand there. Get your ass in here.
我们需要另一个傻瓜
We need another sucker.
去死吧你  斯基齐
Bite me, Skeezy.
我来给你看看新式改良版僵尸叉
Hey, I got to show you the new and improved Z-Whacker.
说起僵尸叉
Hey, speaking of Z-Whacker
那时和你在一起的姑娘怎么样了  她是不是...
what happened to the girl you were with? Did she...
还没  兄弟  我们还是在一起行动
No, man. We're still traveling together.
他们先走一步求助去了
They went ahead looking for help.
我还以为他们到这里了
Kinda thought they'd end up here.
没  我没见过他们
No, haven't seen them.
我一定会好好留意的
And I'm pretty sure I'd notice.
我们这里有大战僵尸
Here we've got our latest innovations
最新开发出的枪械
in zombie fighting technology.
无论是轻武器  很热销哦
Small arms. Hot potato.
围攻武器
Siege weapons.
还是砍脑神器
Brain-obliterators.
只要你能说得出  我们就有
You name it, we got it.
保证你们能高枕无忧
Just sit back, relax,
再也不用为末日发愁了
and forget about the apocalypse.
你们不担心僵尸吗
Aren't you worried about the Zs?
看看周围
Look around.
我们在堪萨斯州荒无人烟的地方
We're in the middle of nowhere Kansas.
四周空空如也  只有几百平方英里的
We're surrounded by hundreds of square miles
休耕农田
of nothing but fallow farmlands.
这里没有僵尸  他们没有食物
There's no Zs here. Nothing for them to eat.
他们都去了大城市
They've all moved on to the big cities.
你别担心
Don't you worry.
我会保护你
I'll protect you.
无论如何  即使有僵尸过来溜达
Yeah, but anyway, if one were to come amble by,
我们也万事俱备时刻准备迎战了  不是吗
to say we're prepared is an understatement, right?
那里就是福吧
Uh, over there is the FU-Bar.
里头出售最棒的
Home to the finest
事实上可能是从这里到密西西比河之间
and probably actually the only corn whiskey
唯一仅有的玉米还有私酿威士忌
and moonshine between here and the Miss...
矮油  有人急不可待了呀
Whoa. Somebody's thirsty.
听着兄弟  我们需要一辆新车
Listen man, we need a new vehicle.
我们的旧车眼看就要不行了
Ours is dying a slow death.
你能帮我们一把吗
You think you could help us out?
看在往日情面上
You know, for old time's sake?
不行  朋友
No can do, my friend.
我是个商人  不是慈善家
I'm an entrepreneur, not a philanthropist.
不过
But
你们或许能自己赢一辆回来
there might be a way you can help yourself.
我们举办的首届现场僵尸射击大赛
Our first annual live zombie shooting contest.
有什么奖品
What's the prize?
弗农  给朋友们看看头奖奖品
Hey, Vernon. Show our friends here first prize.
这真的是五十口径巴雷特M82狙击步枪吗
That a real 50 caliber M82 Barret?
货真价实
Genuine.
另外我们还随枪附送几百发子弹
Plus we'll even throw in a few hundred rounds of shells.
杀伤力未免太大了
Seems like a little overkill.
没错  不过很多人都喜欢这些家伙
Yeah. But there's a lot of guys who like their toys.
不少人可能愿意用一辆车
A lot of guys who might be willing to trade a vehicle
来换这样一挺漂亮的机枪
for a sweet piece of steel like that 50.
你们懂吗
You know what I mean?
在哪报名
Where do I sign up?
小伙子  你认为你能行是吗
You think you got what it takes, little man?
这孩子可以用弹弓
This kid could kill a Z at 50 yards away
杀死50码开外的僵尸
with a rubber band and a paper clip.
好的  在福吧报名
All right. Sign ups in the FU-Bar.
如果你们赢了
If you do win
同时想把奖品去换一辆酷毙了的汽车的话
and you want to trade it for a bad mama jama vehicle,
可以去找沃纳梅克
you wanna talk to a guy named Wannamaker.
如果你们还有别的事可以找弗农
Oh and if you want side action talk to Vernon.
但是别和那人打赌
But do not bet against that guy.
达伦·库柏
Darren Cooper.
前突击队狙击手
Ex Ranger Sniper.
已证实在阿富汗射杀了50人呢
Fifty confirmed kills in Afghanistan.
来一个杀一个
Lethal as they come.
你不能让她再这样下去了
You got to do something about her.
我可不会等任何人
I'm not waiting for anybody.
我知道  摩菲  你冷静点
I know, Murphy. Keep your shorts on.
你在这见到一个叫沃纳梅克的人了吗
Have you seen a guy in here named Wannamaker?
什么  我们是在交朋友吗
What, are we making friends now?
有人知道谁是沃纳梅克吗
Anybody know anybody in here named Wannamaker?
谁要找他
Who wants to know?
我们想做个交易
Oh, we're just lookin' to trade.
你懂的  有个小生意
You know just a little business.
我朋友说他可能有辆车
Yeah, my friend said he might have a vehicle.
是的
Yeah.
沃纳梅克有车
Wannamaker's got cars.
你知道他在哪吗
Do you know where he is?
你好  醒醒
Uh, hey! Uh, hello!
他是不会醒的
He's not gonna wake up.
沃纳梅克只要睡着  就不会醒的
Once Wannamaker's down, he's down.
48小时后再来找他吧
Check back in forty-eight hours.
那你呢
Well what about you?
你看起来像是有车的人
You look like a car man.
我不开车
I don't drive cars.
我开的是机器
I drive machines.
那你有不要的机器吗
Any, uh, any machine you'd be willing to let go of?
看情况
Depends.
你们用什么来交换
What do you got to trade?
亲爱的  别担心  你不值这个价
Don't worry, darlin'. You're not worth it.
什么都比不上福曼移动站
Ain't nothing as sweet as the Formanmobile.
一等奖那个狙击步枪怎么样
What about that 50 caliber first prize?
就算你们赢了  那奖品是很好
Even if you do win, and that's a big if,
但我也不会卖福曼移动站
the Formanmobile is not for sale.
生物柴油
Bio-diesel.
太阳能
Solar-powered.
僵尸来了  噪声很小
Quiet as they come.
有厨房
Kitchen.
浴室
Bathroom.
完全可再生的内部管道系统
Fully regenerative internal plumbing system
搭配防腐交联聚乙烯管
complete with marine grade PEX fittings.
内有NSV机枪  火焰投射器
Built in, we got an NSV machine gun, flame thrower,
击晕棒  枪榴弹发射器  末日汽笛
cattle gun, grenade launcher, doom whistle,
还有常见的
plus the usual
轮刺  一切应有尽有
wheel spikes, all that.
我逗你们呢
Look at me teasin' ya.
你们休想觊觎我的宝贝
Ain't no way you're getting your hands on my baby.
好吧
Oh, okay.
他喝醉了
Well he's drunk.
孩子  我们过去报名
Let's go get you signed up, kid.
我要去方便一下
I got to drain the lizard king.
福曼
Hey, Forman!
福曼  你还好吗
Forman, you okay?
福曼
Forman.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
放开我
Get off me!
僵尸  天呐
Zombie. Hell.
你是什么东西
What are you?!
僵尸
Zombie.
希望他们能收下那辆破车当报名费
Let's hope they'll take a busted up truck for the entrance fee.
下一个  准备好你的报名费
Next. Have your entry fees ready.
没有钥匙  不要啊
No key. Come on.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen.
你们期待已久的时刻到了
It's that moment you've all been waiting for.
枪击比赛开始
It's shootin' time.
我是一万
I'm Ten Thousand.
把你打得落花流水不需要知道你的名字
Don't need to know your name to kick your ass.
报了名的枪手
Registered shooters!
请在指定的射击线上击中你的目标
Please hit your marks on the designated firing line!
首轮比赛射击线离目标100码
All right, this first round takes place 100 yards out.
当我说瞄准目标  你就瞄准僵尸
When I announce the target Z, you aim.
当我说开枪  你就开始射击
When I say fire, you shoot.
如果你没击中  你就出局
If you miss, you're out.
一次定胜负的比赛  各位
This is sudden death, people.
因为我们最近的日子就是这样
Cuz there ain't no other way these days.
站在这边的斯基齐是裁判
Skeezy over here's gonna be judge.
裁判说的就是最终结果  好吗
And what the judge says is final. Yeah?
最后的赢家将得到点50口径重机枪
Last man standing gets the 50!
告诉他们第二名的奖品是什么  弗农
Tell them what second place gets them, Vernon!
一套切肉排刀
Set of steak knives!
冠军非你莫属  孩子
You're a shoe-in, kid.
你失去了身边的人吗
You lost someone?
似乎这是大家最近都在经历的事
Seems like that's all we ever do these days.
会让人疑惑还要不要活下去
Makes you wonder if it's even worth being around people anymore.
是失去家人吗
Was it family?
我猜得没错
Yeah, that's what I thought.
你需要多喝几杯
You're gonna need a few more of these.
准备好了吗  枪手们
You ready, shooters?!
让我们射杀一些僵尸吧
Let's... kill... some... zombies!
首轮比赛
Round one!
我们的第一个目标出现啦
There's the first target right there.
蓄着长发的嬉皮士
Hippie dude with the long hair.
开枪
Fire!
好了  是谁没击中
All right, who shot grandma?
沃里斯  你出局了
Voorhees, you're out!
下一个目标  穿运动裤的肥猪流
Next target! Hipster with the sweatpants!
开枪
Fire!
你没事吧  福曼
You okay, Forman?
你脸色不太好
You don't look so good.
流血了吗
You bleeding?
何止流血  你个白痴  我被咬了
I'm more than bleeding, you idiot. I'm bit!
被一个僵尸长相的家伙咬了
Some zombie-looking mother bit me!
如果真被僵尸咬了  你会变僵尸的
If it was a zombie, you'd have turned.
我不知道他是什么
I don't know what he was.
但他不对劲
But he wasn't right!
他像某种动物或者什么的
He's like some kind of animal or something.
他拿走了我福曼移动站的钥匙
He took the keys to the Formanmobile.
他会把你们的东西也偷走
And he'll steal your stuff too.
而且谁知道他还会咬谁
And who knows who else he's gonna bite.
你  你  你
You. You. You.
我要找到那家伙
I'm finding that dude
在他有机会咬别人之前
and I'm taking him out before he has a chance
做掉他
to bite anyone else.
谁要跟我一起去
Who's with me?!
-去做掉他  -我们会做掉他的
- Let's get him! - We'll get him!
走吧
Let's go!
还有什么是我需要知道的吗
Anything I need to know?
那不是僵尸
It's not a zombie.
好像发生了非自然灾难
It's like some kind of unnatural disaster.
是可怕的僵尸侵袭
A freakin' zunami.
这不是测试  重复  这不是测试
This is not a test. Repeat. This is not a test.
这是市民Z的紧急广播系统  发生了
This is the Citizen Z emergency broadcast system. There's a...
涌进现象  僵尸涌进
a flood, a zombie flood,
大面积的僵尸侵袭
a zunami of biblical proportions.
如果你在堪萨斯西部附近
If you're anywhere in the vicinity of Western Kansas,
你得...
you need to...
妈蛋  你得赶紧逃命啊
Screw it. You need to get the hell out now!
如果你在哈密尔顿  格里利
If you're in Hamilton, Greeley,
威奇托  卡尼县区域
Wichita, Kearney County area,
赶紧逃命
get the hell out now!
就是他  就是那个僵尸咬了我
That's him! That's the Z that bit me!
为什么我有种不祥的预感
Why do I have a bad feeling about that?
就是他
That's him!
你们好  有事吗
Hey, guys. What's up?
他不是僵尸  他还会说话呢
He's not a zombie. He's talkin'.
我刚才是说他长得像僵尸
I said he looked like a zombie.
你看看他长成什么样
I mean look at him.
不过那都不是事  他偷走了我的钥匙
But it doesn't matter. He stole my keys!
呃  他在撒谎
Uh, that's a lie.
那你在我车边上干什么呢
Then what are you doing at my machine?
搜他身
Search him.
是僵尸
It is a Z!
我就说吧
I told you.
我要弄死这家伙
I am gonna put him down.
不
No!
僵尸
Zombies!
快走  离开这儿
Let's go! Get out of here!
大家好枪法啊
Nice shootin', everybody!
易货桌那边管存货的人
People checking out inventory over at the barter tables,
小心流弹  谢谢合作
watch stray bullets. Thanks.
怎么了
What?
你说呀
你咬了那哥们儿吗
You bit that guy?
没有  不是  打了一架而已
No. No. It was just a fight.
那你拿什么跟他打的
Well what'd you fight him with?
因为他在流血  流得还不少
Because he was bleeding. A lot.
我不清楚  他喝醉了  我没看出来
I dunno. He was drunk. I didn't see.
我试着帮他  他还反赖我偷他的东西
I tried to help him, and then he accused me of stealing from him.
你试着帮他吗
You tried to help him?
算了吧  兄弟  跟我说实话
Come on, man. Level with me.
说就说  我们要用车  比他更急着用
Screw it. We need a vehicle, and we need it more than he does.
因为我是人类的救世主
Because I'm the savior of humanity.
还记得吗  第一要务
Remember? Priority number one.
所以该干什么就干什么  偷点东西又怎样
So we do what we got to do. And sometimes we steal stuff.
你到底咬没咬人
Did you bite him?
多克  你懂我的
Doc, you know me.
我不是禽兽
I am not an animal.
你牙齿怎么了
What happened to your tooth?
听着
Look.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
我去找其他人
I'm gonna go get the others.
你真让我失望
I'm very disappointed.
还剩五位参赛选手
We got five contestants left.
下一目标
Next target.
带牛仔帽的
Cowboy hat.
开火
Fire!
斯奈德  出局
Snyder, you're out.
马利根  出局
Mulligan, you're out.
枪法不错  马利根
Good shootin', Mulligan.
明年再接再厉  如果明年你还活着
Better luck next year. If there is a next year.
好啦  还有三位参赛选手
All right, we got three contestants left!
我们要增加筹码  把距离拉到400码
So let's up the ante and let's take it out to 400 yards!
我们得赶紧走了
We need to get out of here.
不行  再等等
We can't, not yet.
他还没被淘汰吗
He's still in it?
是呀
Oh yeah.
我们的小万万真棒
That's our boy.
你朋友都不把你给埋起来
Your friends didn't even cover you up.
一群野蛮人
Savages.
你没变异
You didn't turn.
好啦  我们还剩三位参赛选手
All right, we got three contestants left!
继续加大难度
Let's up the ante!
把僵尸引到500码外
Let's take her out 500 yards!
你为什么叫一万
Why are you called Ten Thousand?
我计划杀一万只僵尸
It's how many Zs I plan to kill.
你已经杀了多少
How many you got?
不算上今天的话...
Not counting today...
一共杀了2119只
Two thousand one hundred nineteen.
我今天会杀得比你多的
I'll still get more than you today.
有可能
Maybe.
但也不一定
Maybe not.
朝着穿工装裤的那家伙
The dude with the coveralls!
开火
Fire!
不好意思  你出局了哟
Sorry! You're gone!
行啊  小伙子  你可以的
You got this, kid. You got this!
准备好缴械投降了吗
You ready to give up?
休想
Never.
休想?
Never?
如果你是想用这种方法让我抓狂
If this is your attempt at trying to psych me out,
那你就很不幸地失算了
you're failing miserably.
集中注意力
Stay focused.
那枪我拿定了
That gun is mine.
有僵尸
Zombies.
僵尸闯进来了
Zombies inside the perimeter!
各位听好  我们
Okay, listen up everybody. We...
我们需要几个人去消灭几个僵尸
we need a few people to go check and clean up some Zs
去看看边界那边怎么回事
and see what's going on at the perimeter.
各位  如果不消灭这些个僵尸
Look people, no one's gonna win anything
我们大伙儿谁都尽不了兴  赢不了枪
unless we stop these Zs from spoiling our fun!
你们说是吧
All right?
待在这
Stay here.
继续比赛
You keep shooting.
他们从哪来的
Where the hell they all come from?
你现在成了僵尸了
So you're a zombie now.
真是太好了
That's just perfect.
这说明你跟其他人一样  满嘴扯谎
I guess that makes you a liar like everyone else.
不不  没关系
No, no, it's okay.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
要说该怪谁
If it's anybody's fault,
只能怪我
it's mine.
我该放聪明点的  查理
I shoulda known better, Charlie.
悔不当初啊
I shoulda.
但你是这么的...
But you were so...
我们刚上路的时候
I used to just watch you
我还观察过你
back when we started.
我知道你不想谈这个
I know you don't like to talk about this.
你喜欢杀僵尸  还越杀越兴奋
But it doesn't make you bad that you like to kill them
但这不意味着你是坏人
and it turns you on.
不是的
It doesn't.
所以我才相信你
It's what made me believe in you.
你真是太厉害了  哥们
You were such a badass. Oh man.
你不像那些个盲目的白痴
Not like those blind idiots
总是做着回到往日好生活的春秋大梦
always dreaming of a life that will never come back.
不  你不盲目
No, you weren't blind.
你看清了真相  你坦然面对
You saw it, and you faced it.
所以当你告诉我还有出路
So when you told me there was a way,
还能活下去的时候
a way to live again,
我信了你
I believed you.
你让我信了你
You made me believe you.
你怎么能这么对我
How could you do that to me?
你给了我...
You gave me...
希望
hope.
你让我  我们希望
That I, that we,
还能过过小日子  而且我...
could have some kind of life. And I...
我为此爱过你
I loved you for that.
结果这一点把你害死了
Then it got you killed.
你心存希望
You had hope,
但希望削弱了你
and it made you weak.
也削弱了我
It made me weak.
你怎么能这样  查理
How could you do that, Charlie?
你怎么能
How could you
给了我这么多希望
give me all of that
然后一下子全夺走
and then take it away?
你怎么能...死
How could you... die?
你为什么要死
How could you die?
你怎么忍心死
趁还有得亲
Just in case.
如果你没有活下去的理由
If you don't have a reason to live,
还不如死了
you might as well die.
你就是这样
That's all you did.
因为你给了我理由
Cuz you gave me a reason.
很好的理由
And it was a nice one.
一个非常美好的谎言
A beautiful lie, really.
那种美好再也不会有了
It won't ever be beautiful like that.
但我会找到活下去的理由
But I'll find a reason to live.
我会的
I will.
我仁慈地结束你的生命
I give you mercy.
好  现在靶距500码  不能再远了
Okay! We're 500 yards out, and we can't go any further!
强者生出
So best shot wins!
赢家通吃哦
This is for all the cookies!
第一轮
First up!
法官
The judge!
开火
Fire!
女士优先
Ladies first.
一边去  叫谁女士
Screw you. I'm no lady.
那好
kay.
打它
Beat that.
好啊
Kay.
两发子弹穿同一个洞
Two bullets, one hole.
看来是平局了啊
I'm callin' it a tie.
女士们  先生们  女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen. Ladies and gentlemen.
现在比赛打得难解难分
We got ourselves a barn burner here.
比赛要进入骤死加时阶段
This thing's going into sudden death overtime!
都到我这来
So come on over and see me
最后一轮之前  请下注
and put down your bets before the next round!
对  大家都下注
All right, people. Place your bets.
来吧  押吧
Come on. Put them down.
该死
Oh shit.
我们有新把子了
We got a couple of frash runner.
你先打  我扫剩下的
You first. I'll clean up.
我们的司机
Our driver!
它们有腊肉吃了
They're getting Side Meat!
仁慈地了结他吧
Give the man mercy!
打得好
Nice shootin'.
现在冠军产生了
Hey, we've got ourselves a winner!
干得漂亮  孩子
Nice job, kid.
现在领奖  然后快走
Now let's get your prize and get the hell out of here.
你也好枪法
Good shootin'.
这是胜利者的战利品
To the victor goes the spoils!
健健康康的地活着  现在快找地方躲吧
Kill in good health, kid. Now get out of dodge.
收拾家伙了
Closing time!
快快快  快快快
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
我快没子弹了
I'm getting low on ammo.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
这些僵尸是从哪冒出来的
Where are these Zs coming from?
不知道  我爸爸跑哪去了
I dunno. But where the hell is my dad?
我们不能久留了
We can't wait much longer.
布莉塔妮
Brittany!
他在那
There he is.
布莉塔妮
Brittany!
我没子弹了
I'm out.
第2025个
Two thousand two hundred five.
好枪法  孩子
Nice shooting, kid!
快  布莉特  我们得走了
Come on, Brit! We got to go!
等等
Wait!
拿上这个吧
Take this.
你比我更应该得到
You deserve it more than I do.
真的  我真心希望你收下
Really. I want you to have it.
布莉特  我们必须走了
Brit. We got to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝你好运  孩子
Good luck, kid.
大哥  您是从哪冒出来的
Where'd you come from?
你好像好点了
You're looking better.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
我们还要等他多久
How much longer are we gonna wait for him?
不会很久了
Not much.
他会回来的
He'll be here.
-快射啊  -我没法瞄准
- Get him! - I can't get shot!
抓稳他  孩子
Hold him steady, kid!
我做不到
I can't!
你这是往哪开
You know where you're going?
朝着太阳的方向
Followin' the sun.
要是查理...
It's what Charlie...
他就会这么做
It's what he would do.
希望我们能赶上麦克和艾迪
I hope we catch up with Mack and Addy.
是啊  我也希望
Yeah, I hope so too.
各位
Well, people.
若不是我们已经身处大灾变之中
If we weren't already in an apocalypse,
这绝对是个灾难将至的明显信号
this would be a damn obvious sign.
比大灾变更糟糕的状况叫什么呢  而它...
What do you call something worse than an apocalypse? Because
就在我的眼前  不管它叫什么
this is it. Whatever it is.
成群  蜂拥  海啸  一望无际
Swarm, horde, tsunami. There's no end in sight.
如果你身在他们前进的方向上
If you're not already west of this thing,
你最好赶紧动身  因为根本不可能闯过去
you better get moving. There's no getting through it.
不可能逃脱
There's no outrunning it.
你必须找个安全的地方躲起来
You got to find some place safe and hide.
祝你们好运  各位
Good luck, people.
祝你们平安
And Godspeed.